

Professional Summary

Gururaja Murthy

Profile: Project Manager / Agile Scrum Master/QA Leader

An Experienced and Certified IT Professional with extensive 18+ years of experience in Product/Project Management, Agile Scrum Master ,QA Test Management , Defect Management, Release Management, People Management , Outsource management and Client Management in Multi-Million Dollar Software Development Applications for Industries as Banking Financial Insurance Mortgage, Health Care & Life Science Management, Security, ERP, Airline, Logistics Telecom , Supply chain Management, Manufacturing, Automobiles, Manufacturing and Retail/E- Commerce.

Education and Credentials

- Master's in Computer Application First Class
- Project Management Certification Kent State University (PMP)
- Certified Scrum Master from Scum Alliance CSM
- Certified Product Owner -CSPO

| Core Competency | Technical Skill set |
|-------------------------------|--|
| Specialized Technology | Mobility, Digital, SOA/Web services, IOS, Android, Mongo DB, Cloud- |
| | HP/VMware, and Data Analytics. |
| Software Development | Java, J2ee, EJB, JSP, HTML, CSS, Java script, XML, Microsoft Dot Net, |
| technology | Angular JS, Android SDK and IOS |
| Database/ Big Data | Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Mongo DB. |
| Functional Areas | Digital, Client Server Applications, Web Applications, Mainframes, |
| | Mobility, Cloud Platform. |
| Enterprise System/Business | Actuate(BIRT), Cognos and SSRS |
| Intelligence | |
| Data warehouse/Analytics | Microsoft Integration services (DTS and SSIS), Informatica, Data Stage |
| | |
| Sustained engineering or | Hot fix, Patch, Upgrade, compatibility, Regression, Release and |
| Critical engineering services | Deployment |
| Test Management | HP ALM, Rational Test Manager, IBM Test Management Tool, |
| | Microsoft Test Manager |
| Test Automation and CI/CD | Rational Suite Enterprise, HPUFT, Load Runner 9.0, BPT, Selenium and |
| | Ranorex, Jira, Jenkins |
| Defect Management system | Rational Clear Quest, PVCS Tracker, Test Director, JIRA, Mantis and |
| | TFS |
| SQA | Reviews, Internal Audits, Process Health check |
| | (CMMi- level 5) |
| Process | Agile, Kanban, RUP, V-Model |
| Performance testing | Load runner, Rational performance tester, Apache-JMeter |

| SOA track | SOAP UI, REST services, ITKO LISA |
|----------------------------|--|
| Infrastructure Track | IBM Appscan, Vmware, Clustered apps |
| Airline Track | Ticketing system, Inflight Exchange. |
| Healthcare package | Medco express scripts |
| Telecom Track | Billing packages from BT and AT&T |
| logistics Track | FedEx ship manager |
| Security Track | IBM Appscan, VMware, Clustered testing |
| Oracle packages track | Siebel CRM 8.0, People soft HRMS |
| SAP packages track | SAP SD and CRM |
| Business process | PEGA PRPC |
| management | |
| Sales force packages track | Sales force CRM |
| Configuration Management | Rational Clear Case, Visual Source Safe, PVCS Dimension. |
| /Release Management | |
| Mobile Application | Android, IOS, Blackberry, Windows phone OS |
| Development | |

Key IT Projects/Solutions Delivered for Global Fortune Customers – U.S.A, U.K, Canada, Germany, France, Australia Singapore, South Africa and Malaysia.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Experience Highlights:

MINDTREE Limited – Project -Test Manager/Scrum Master

Feb 2016-Present (USA)

Client Name : Fortune listed BFSI client – North Carolina

Description : Life, RPS and Annuity Insurance applications (IOS, Android, Web Platform)

- Responsible for Creation of the Project plan and Test plan
- Responsible for People Management; Responsible Scheduling, Tracking and Reporting;
- Responsible for Resource allocation (people, hardware, software, and facilities);
- Responsible for Metric Preparation and Reporting;
- Responsible for Managing, supervising, and assessing team performance
- Responsible for Defining project scope, goals and
- Deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with senior management and stakeholders;
- Responsible for Liaising with project stakeholders on an ongoing basis & ensuring Customer Satisfaction;
- Responsible for reports publishing with upward management
- Agile Project Track: Helping team regarding Grooming of user stories and Estimation (JIRA, Scrumwise, Confluence).
- Use Product Backlog and come up with a release plan & Sprint plan during Sprint 0.

- Sprint Planning and Story Point decision using pocker card with the agile team.
- Daily Scrum call/Stand-ups with the Agile team to identify any blocker/impediment.
- Resolve Blocker/issues immediately collaborating with required interface team/stakeholders.
- Continuous Integration and Delivery: DevOPS, Automation testing. Daily status updates.
- Sprint Review at the last day of the sprint with the PO to demo the shipped product.
- Conduct Sprint Retrospective post the completion of the sprint. Come up with action items.
- Effectively use of Collaborative tools and JIRA/Confluence tool for Agile process, time tracking, metrics.

Mphasis Limited- An HP Company: Agile Scrum Master | Project Manager | QA-Test Manager. March 2010-Feb 2016 (U.S.A. and Bangalore)

Project Name : Sigma BI for AIG

Technology : IOS and Android Apps, Business analytics-IBM Data Stage, DB2, Informatica,

Cognos Reports, Adobe CQ5, IOS and Android app.

Project Name : American Airlines SABRE- Trip case;
Role : Project Manager /Scrum Master

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment: Software Development Track

- Sprint Release planning, Daily Standup meeting, Problem solutions, Sprint Demo and Retrospective
- Facilitating Scrum of Scrum for offshore Scrum teams in US and India
- Managing the overall performance and delivery of cross-functional
- Facilitating sprint planning as Scrum master for multiple Scrum teams
- Publicizing the team's progress and successes to make sure they are highly visible
- To product owner's/ stakeholders. Ensuring the team together till the release completion
- Ensuring the transition of Projects from Waterfall to Agile

Maintenance Projects/Testing Projects Track

- Responsible for Creation of Project plan and the Test plan
- Responsible for People Management; Responsible Scheduling, Tracking and Reporting
- Responsible for Resource allocation (people, hardware, software, and facilities)
- Responsible for Metric Preparation and Reporting;
- Responsible for Managing, supervising, and assessing team performance
- Responsible for Defining project scope, goals and Deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with senior management and stakeholders
- Responsible for Liaising with project stakeholders on an ongoing basis & ensuring Customer Satisfaction
- Responsible for automation using Ranorex version 5.0
- Responsible for Set up and manage project expectations with team members and other stakeholders
- Hiring and retaining talent into the organization and projects;

- Responsible for Coaching, mentor, motivate and supervise Project team members and influence them to take positive action and accountability for their assigned work
- Develop and deliver progress reports, proposals, requirements documentation and presentations
- Responsible for proactively managing changes in project scope
- Identify potential crises and devise contingency plans
- Responsible for Defining project success criteria and disseminate them to involved parties throughout Project life cycle and Delivery

Project Name : Schwab Index Advantage for Charles Schwab Corporation

Technology : Microsoft team foundation server; Microsoft Integration services, Microsoft

reporting services; Actuate Reporting system, Cloud computing Platform.

Role : Test Manager/Leader

Description : Schwab Retirement planning application

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment

• Reaching agreement with client about the assignment and expectations

- Ensuring test infrastructure is available on time
- Keeping the issue administration continually updated
- Responsible for end to end delivery from offshore team.
- Responsible for planning, execution and reporting of test
- Conducted Security testing & Performance testing.

Project Name : CAFÉ – Customer Automation for Future Endeavour for FedEx

Technology : HP ALM, Business process testing, quick Test Pro

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment

- Responsible for the team of 30 testing resources
- Responsible End to end testing delivery to the customer
- Responsible for the team appraisals
- Responsible for defect analysis and management
- Responsible for the process management
- Responsible for the customer management
- Responsible for both offshore delivery teams in Bangalore and Mangalore

Marlabs Software (P) Ltd - Project Leader /Release Manager (Aug 2008 – March 2010)

Project Name : In-Flight Exchange (IFX4) ™ Product suite = Supply chain management

for Air line services for gate gourmet Customers

Technology : SAP R/34.0, SAP Test Acceleration and Optimization, Quality center, Loadrunner

Client : Gate Gourmet Inc. U.S.A

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Responsible for application test management for multiple projects
- Managed team of 18-20 testers
- Responsible for Estimation and Risk Management
- Interaction with customer on daily basis
- Coordinated with automation team for testing using QTP
- Coordinated with performance test team using Load Runner
- Reported QA team status to executives
- Managed defects using Jira
- SPOC for testing during testing QA, UAT and Production environment.
- Standardize QA standards and practices for the project teams
- Coordinated for tool evaluation and POC (Proof of Concept)
- Collection of Metrics and Reporting to the Management.
- Working closely with Business development team to articulate Business value through Testing solutions and help them to close new accounts (Proposals and SOW's)

Tratum Technologies Pvt. Ltd - QC lead (Dec 2007 – Jul 2008)

Project Name : Prepaid and Post-Paid Billing Systems for British Telecom

Client : British Telecom - U.K.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Day to day test management, reporting and defect management
- Prepared status reports for management and drafted Test Completion Report.
- Member of SEPG
- Ensuring a test infrastructure is available on time.
- Allowing use of all agreed test methodologies
- Support in the Test project proposal creation, Sow's and roadmap for transition
- Coordination and participation in the client application portfolio assessment & estimation
- Managed, planned and allocated test resources for projects.

Mphasis – An EDS Company - Test Lead (Jan 2006 – Jul 2007)

Project : CRM package

Client : Charles Schwab financial corporation

Duration : 01/2006 - 12/2006

Project : Auto-write off
Client : **Xerox Corporation**Duration : 01/2007 - 07/2007

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

Process Improvement

- Prepared requirement clarification tracker to manage requirements.
- Authored gap analysis tracker to manage gap between wire frames And functional specifications.
- Authored release management process for testing team.
- Wrote and maintained Master test plan, Estimations, risks, issues, templates, Review Reports and Test Reports.
- Ensuring adherence to software quality process

Test Management

- Test planning, scheduling and monitoring
- Test estimation using industry standard estimation models.
- Resource recruitment and management
- Single point of contact for testing teams both at Bangalore and Chennai.
- The team establishes testing processes, testing standards, test case designs, defects, and reviews, test reports.
- Migrated several applications from onsite to offshore.
- Managed all types of testing such as Functional, System, Reliability, Performance, Load, Usability, Security, Compatibility, Acceptance, Regression using Manual and Automation Techniques
- Responsible for Defect Tracking and Defect Management.

Client Management

- Regular communication with customers
- Relationship management.
- Reporting the QA status to onsite executives on regular basis
- Providing solutions
- Publish software test deliverables identified during each control point of SDLC, including Test plan, Test cases, Defect and Test reports.
- Support in Test project proposal creation and roadmap for transition

•

People Management

- Control and Monitor the team by giving specified inputs
- Encourage team members to attend training program at least once in 3 months
- Responsible for team members appraisals
- Started new initiatives like celebrating team members marriage anniversaries and birthdays
- Interacting with each team member and prepare growth plan

Contribution to the organization

- Submitted Test management white papers
- Submitted QA handbook to organization
- Member of Testing Competency Interviewer's panel.
- Authored testing process for onsite-offshore delivery model.

Commerce Velocity (India) Pvt. Ltd - Test Lead (Aug 2005 – Jan 2006)

Project Name : Credit Quality Decision Suite this is an integrated solution for Mortgage banking
Client : Mylor financial services, Funding America Wilmington financial services, Bear

Stearns, Green light, NRT, Zero Down Mortgage, AHL, FNLC, VERITAS, Option One.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Managing Multiple leading clients such as Mylor financial services, Funding America Wilmington financial services, Bear Stearns, Green light, NRT, Zero Down Mortgage, AHL, FNLC, VERITAS, Option One.
- Leading a team of 10 resources.
- Managed creation of process for testing
- People management and test management, resource allocation & planning.
- Value add: Test repository creation and management
- Values add: Provide training guidance and growth opportunities for growing staff.
- Values add: improved communication between QA and Dev team.
- Author Release Notes for each deployment of software.
- Provide test results to be used by management as criteria for migration into Production environment(s).
- Test planning and tracking and monitoring.
- Co-coordinating with onsite/client
- Handles all critical issues and reviews with QA Analyst

IBM GLOBAL SERVICES PVT. LTD - Test lead (Jul 2004 – Aug 2005)

Project Name : PBM – Pharmaceutical Benefit Management system for Merck fortune

pharmaceutical company

Client : Merck & Co., Inc

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Leading team of 9-11 QA test engineers.
- Report QA team status to Onsite Executives
- Responsible for Test data creation
- Responsible for multiple applications on Mainframe and Web.
- Development of testing strategy and work assignments among team members.
- Designing of test plans, test cases, reports and its maintenance using Test Management Tool (TMT tool)
- Designing of various templates according to customer specifications
- Responsible for Performance appraisal to team members
- Training the testing team before putting them on production on testing methodologies.
- Hiring resources. Member of the project recruitment team for testing resources.
- Interviewing and scheduling the client interview and member of IBM testing Competency Interviewer's panel.
- Mentored team members in use of Merant PVCS tracker for Defect tracking

- Develop documentation in PPS and Excel to track deliverables
- Interviewed all QA resources and recommended to Dept. Manager and testing Competency R.D.M on hiring.
- Defect tracking and Reporting found for developers using Merant PVCS Tracker
- Signing off the Quality Gates (Delivery to the customer)

Microcon International Ltd – Senior Test Engineer (Feb 2002 - Jun 2004)

Project Name : HMS version 1.0

Hospital Management system;

Client : Parkway Group

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Supervise 4-5 test engineers ensuring proper testing and regression testing was achieved
- Deliverables included Test Plan, Test cases execution reports, Defect reports
- Mentored team members in use of Multi-site Rational Clear Quest for Defect Tracking.
- Monitor schedules
- Lead the Quality Review Process Group within the Team
- Knowledge Transfer to new hired employees to assume QA roles.
- Maintained project statistics, such as defect rate and severity, milestones met.
- Implement Automated Testing Methodology and best practices for QA Team Using Rational Testing suites.
- Developed Modularized Rational Robot automated test scripts for Web and
- Client/Server Applications
- Aid in design and implementation of Load Testing using Rational Load test.
- Utilize Clear Quest for Manual and Automated defect tracking, and Reporting.
- Ensure defects of unit testing and integration testing been closed before Carrying out system testing.

ADS Technologies Pvt. Ltd – Test Engineer (Sep 98 – Dec 2001)

Product : IBS Versions 1.2 and 1.2

Technology : Integrated Business solution – End to end ERP solutions for Retail Industries.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Manual testing. Prepared test cases and test data generation
- System testing and functional testing, Usability testing.
- Bugs found in the Application were entered in Spreadsheet.
- Filing of System test error logs and defining error priorities in test error reports.
- Executed, analyzed and evaluated test results, conducted validation and verification of Software